Divyashree R

Software Engineer (Frontend)

+91 7349234791 div5353@gmail.com Bengaluru, Karnataka www.linkedin.com/in/divyashree-lochan https://divya_portfolio

SUMMARY

A Bengaluru-based Software Engineer - I thrive on bringing creativity to the forefront in the world of technology. With a solid year of experience in **website** and **Content Management System** development using React.js, Redux, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, I constantly strive to enhance my skills in both design and development.

SKILLS

Primary Skills - React.js, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

State Management - Redux, Saga

API Testing - Postman

Version Control - Git

Basics - Angular, Figma.

EXPERIENCE

1. Riversilica, Bengaluru - Software Engineer

NOVEMBER 2022 - Current

i) CMS Migration

Roles & responsibilities - Migrating the entire CMS of an OTT Platform from Angular to React.js.

Project Summary - Worked on a Content Management System (CMS), part of an OTT platform that integrates Webapp, Android, iOS and TV applications—worked on migrating the entire Content Management System from Angular to React.js with improved performance and new features.

Tech Stack - React.js, Redux, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap

ii) Video Wall benchmarking (PoC)

Roles & responsibilities - Created a Proof of Concept to benchmark video player grids that stream videos simultaneously.

Project Summary - Tried and tested with multiple tools like Qt, and finalized on Python with VLC and Tkinter to create 20 video player grids to stream videos on a Linux server.

Tech Stack - Python, Tkinter

iii) News Application CMS (MVP)(ongoing)

Roles & responsibilities - Gathering requirements and researching information for product development.

Project Summary - A news application with live, video and written news in various regional languages.

Tech Stack - React.js, Redux, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap

2. Zuru Services, Bengaluru - Internship

DECEMBER 2020 - MARCH 2021

EDUCATION

City Engineering College - Bachelor of Engineering

AUGUST 2018 - AUGUST 2022

CERTIFICATIONS

Meta - Basics of React.

VOLUNTARY SERVICES

GirlUp Gleam, United Nations Foundation - Content Writer

JULY 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2022

Interact Club, Rotary Club - President

DECEMBER 2013 - MARCH 2016